<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[0C59094503E3440188E33A066781DE26]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[516E9994D7DD45CE8520AB1A27A2B864]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:09:42</_entryCreated><_sequence>13</_sequence><_id>d425c175-37c1-47a7-a41a-a80c9b635d60</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[516E9994D7DD45CE8520AB1A27A2B864]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 13 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 5]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:09:42</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding Ethical and Legal Considerations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson initiates your final assignment: the redesign project.  The project will draw on what you have learned throughout the semester  but will also require you to integrate ideas from this lesson and the  final two lessons. This lesson will introduce ethical and legal issues  that technical writers need to consider when preparing both written and  online documents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one sense, it is very difficult to talk about the ethics of  technical communication because the subject is subtle and complicated  and there are no easy answers. Indeed, the majority of technical  communication situations will contain more gray area than easy,  straightforward solutions. Because most students have experienced  serious ethical dilemmas at school or at work, you already have a  background for thinking about ethical matters. But experience is not  enough; you also need training to help you recognize and understand  ethical dilemmas in technical communication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people want to be told what they should do when they  confront ethical dilemmas. Sometimes students think that reading a  chapter on ethics will make them ethical people. But you cannot learn  how to be ethical. Rather, you need to understand how ethicists frame  issues so that you can think about your own ethical issues more clearly  and sensitively. In other words, being ethical involves ongoing work on a  process of reasoning that accounts for the many factors in any ethical  situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions of legal considerations are similarly challenging because  workers do not necessarily see themselves as being representatives of  their organizations. But when employees communicate, they represent the  ethical stance of their organizations, and this ethical stance is often a  matter of legal concern. You need to learn to see that the law is our  society's principal means of manifesting its deepest ethical beliefs.  Often there are liability cases that focus our attention on the  relationship between ethics and the law. For example, an image of a  child operating a small appliance implies that children can use the  appliance safely. This implication has an ethical dimension: at what age  should children operate the appliance? It would be easy to employ an  image in which the age of a child was difficult to discern. The image  also has a legal dimension: the company may be held responsible for  injury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;explain      why technical communicators need to understand basic ethical and legal      principles;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;understand      the basics of four different bodies of law  relevant to technical      communication: copyright law, trademark law,  contract law, and liability      law;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;analyze      a code of conduct;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;define      whistleblowing;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;list the seven principles of ethical communication and      use these principles to meet workplace obligations; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;examine the ethical implications of your own writing      and communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Monday, June 23 by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read Chapter 2 of &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Lesson+12+Commentary&quot; title=&quot;Lesson 12 Commentary&quot;&gt;Lesson 12 Commentary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Complete the      Self-Study Quiz for Chapter 2 of the textbook,     available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bcs.bedfordstmartins.com/techcomm10e/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;front page of TechCommWeb&lt;/a&gt;. Pay particular      attention to any questions that you miss, and review relevant parts of the      chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Review the instructions for our last assignment, the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Redesign+Project+Assignment&quot; title=&quot;Redesign Project&quot;&gt;Redesign Project&lt;/a&gt;,by reading the assignment sheet very, very carefully. If you have questions about the assignment, post them to the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Redesign+Project+Discussion&quot;&gt;Redesign Project discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;. If you don't have questions at this point, be sure to read any posts  to that discussion forum anyway, because you'll benefit from  reading my answers to your classmates' questions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;For this assignment, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to choose a document to redesign (see the instruction sheet for guidelines) and have me  approve it. Post the document you plan to redesign (or a link, if it&amp;rsquo;s a stable website) to the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Redesign+Project+Approval&quot;&gt;approval drop box&lt;/a&gt;. I will let you know as soon as possible whether I approve of your choice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools for this Lesson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>