<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[FB159C0DEB414B5D8ECA00B987AB914E]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[0F56920809C648DBBAA92AB97C820F54]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:02:54</_entryCreated><_sequence>3</_sequence><_id>7873cc80-4dbc-4780-b655-e51050e236eb</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[0F56920809C648DBBAA92AB97C820F54]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 3 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 1  ]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:02:54</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;h2&gt;Analyzing Your Audience and Purpose&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson amplifies two characteristics of technical communication that you learned about in the previous lesson: technical communication addresses particular readers (audience) and helps readers solve problems (purpose). Understanding audience and purpose is critical to any technical communication task. Thus, the draft worksheet for your Basic Rhetorical Analysis (which you&amp;rsquo;ll be completing this lesson) asks you to focus on who your document was created for and why. The following overview will help you prepare to think about audience and purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Audience analysis, a basic principle of rhetoric for centuries, is considered today by many researchers and teachers to be the bedrock of technical communication. Many students have not thought much about the concept of audience because they have never had to consider it. Almost all of their writing has been directed to a single audience, not to multiple audiences. Typically, that audience has been the instructor. Unlike real audiences, the teacher has almost invariably known more about the subject than has the writer, thus making the writing situation even more unrealistic. In this course, your teacher will not always be your audience, and the sample documents you analyze were not written for your teacher. In other words, you are being asked to engage authentic writing situations with real audiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might also find purpose to be a challenging concept. Most students have had only one main purpose in all their writing: to show sufficient knowledge or skill to earn a high grade in an academic course. Students often consider writing to be an audition, not a useful or necessary communication of ideas and information. However, as you will see in this course, writing is an integral part of day-to-day work, not an obstacle to that work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;recognize the importance of analyzing audience and purpose when planning a document;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;classify readers into primary and secondary audiences;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;identify individual characteristics of an audience or multiple audiences;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;write text to meet the needs of expert, technician, manager, and general reader audiences;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;explain the impact of cultural variables on technical documents;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;choose strategies for communicating more effectively with a multicultural audience;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;define the purpose or purposes of a technical document;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;know how to revise information for a new audience and purpose; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;apply your knowledge of audience and purpose as you revise your Basic Rhetorical Analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due by Tuesday at 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read Chapter 5 of &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit your initial post to &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Week3+Discussion1&quot;&gt;Discussion 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Compose and submit your full draft of Project 1 through your &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Basic+Rhetorical+Analysis+Draft+Forums&quot;&gt;team discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due by Thursday at 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reply to some of the posts of your classmates in &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Week3+Discussion1&quot;&gt;Discussion 1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Carefully read each of the papers in your team forum (I will assign you to team groups of 3 or 4). Fill out a separate &lt;a title=&quot;Project 1 Review Worksheet&quot; href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Project+1+Review+Worksheet&quot;&gt;review worksheet&lt;/a&gt; for each paper you read.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit the review worksheets for your peers' papers through the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Basic+Rhetorical+Analysis+Draft+Forums&quot;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt;. You will want to use this forum space to continue discussion about your draft work, ask for clarification of comments, and ask follow-up questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due by Sunday at 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reply to some of the posts of your classmates in &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Week3+Discussion2&quot;&gt;Discussion 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read the feedback your peers gave you and review the assignment sheet one more time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Revise your paper. Revisions should not be superficial; your final version should look significantly different from your original draft.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit your final paper to the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Project+1+Final+Dropbox&quot;&gt;Project 1 Final Dropbox&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools for this Lesson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>