<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[C682B24EC5614EC4A7C9149D4B1E0938]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[74D75FD46FE84EC193F3AAC416D9FEED]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:06:09</_entryCreated><_sequence>6</_sequence><_id>58ac6af0-3643-49d4-997d-0706dbb4085a</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[74D75FD46FE84EC193F3AAC416D9FEED]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 6 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 2]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:06:09</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drafting and Revising Definition and Descriptions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lesson combines two important elements of technical 
communication: definition and description. Although you will sometimes 
encounter these elements separately, more often than not they are used 
together to help explain an object or a process. The assignment we’ll 
begin this week will ask you to focus on description, but there will be 
opportunities for definitional work as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People generally have little trouble with parenthetical definitions, 
single words or short phrases that provide clarification. Sentence 
definitions, however, are more difficult because they require a more 
formal structure of categorization. Many people find it difficult to 
choose an appropriate category for the term they are defining. The 
problem is that they either cannot choose a sufficiently narrow category
 to make the distinguishing characteristics meaningful or are so used to
 sliding into the definition without a noun in the category (&quot;A PDA is 
what is used . . .&quot;) that they cannot understand the concept of using a 
category. Extended definitions usually give people little trouble 
because they are less formal than sentence definitions. If you have a 
good grasp of paragraphing and understand the subject being defined, the
 extended definition will come fairly easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Descriptions of objects and processes encompass definition but also 
other writing elements. Most writers find it fairly simple to gather all
 the information they need to write an effective introduction to a 
description. Sometimes, however, they have trouble deciding just how 
much information their audience and purpose requires. A related 
difficulty is that they sometimes answer the five basic questions 
discussed in the chapter in separate sentences. The cause of this 
problem is easy to understand: they want to make sure all the necessary 
information is included. They worry less about the style of the 
description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you understand how to write an effective introduction, you should 
have little trouble with the part-by-part or step-by-step description 
because it involves the same process. Two problems sometimes occur. Some
 writers fail to distinguish major items from minor items. For example, a
 student might write a description of a bicycle that contains an 
unnecessarily elaborate description of the seat: the material it is made
 of, the type of hardware, the method of adjusting its height, and so 
forth. The second common problem is some students' inability to properly
 sequence an item-by-item description. Sometimes, they fail to follow 
through on the operational sequence of the mechanism or process. This 
can also be a problem in the conclusion of an item-by-item description, 
which may fail to match the rest of the description in terms of sequence
 or identification of major items. Paying attention to these potential 
problems as you write should result in a more effective description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;explain      the role of definitions and descriptions in various kinds of technical      communication; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;use      an understanding of a technical document's audience and 
purpose to select      effective kinds of definitions and descriptions 
to write; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;write      effective parenthetical, sentence, and extended definitions; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;identify      the most effective place for a definition based on a document's audience      and purpose; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;write an effective description of an object or a      process.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Activities due on Monday, June 9 by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read the sections on &quot;Definitions&quot; and &quot;Descriptions,&quot; pp 564-581 in Chapter 20 of &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;MATCH=Lesson+8+Commentary&quot; title=&quot;Lesson 8 Commentary&quot;&gt;Lesson 8 Commentary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Complete the Self-Study Quiz for the relevant parts of Chapter 20 of the textbook, available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bcs.bedfordstmartins.com/techcomm10e/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;front page of TechCommWeb&lt;/a&gt;. Pay particular attention to any questions that you miss, and review relevant parts of the      chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the instructions for the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;MATCH=Technical+Definition+and+Description+Assignment&quot; title=&quot;Technical Definition and Description Assignment&quot;&gt;Technical Definition and Description&lt;/a&gt;
 by reading the assignment sheet very, very carefully. If you have questions about the assignment, post
 them to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cms.psu.edu/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp; WCU=CRSCNT&amp;MATCH=Technical+Definition+and+Description+Discussion&quot;&gt;Technical Definition and Description discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.
 If you don't have questions at this point, be sure to read any posts 
to that discussion forum anyway, because you'll benefit from 
reading my answers to your classmates' questions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Review the Interactive Sample Document, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bcs.bedfordstmartins.com/techcomm9e/default.asp#498169__639469__&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Introducing a Description&lt;/a&gt;,” on TechCommWeb “. The sample document provides the 
introduction to a technical description and six questions for 
analysis. Consider these questions carefully in order to develop a 
sense of how to write an introduction (often the hardest part of 
writing a description).
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do some initial planning before you begin writing your own Technical      Definition and Description. Fill out the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;MATCH=Technical+Definition+Planning+Worksheet&quot; title=&quot;Technical Definition Planning Worksheet&quot;&gt;Technical Definition and Description planning worksheet&lt;/a&gt; and upload it to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cms.psu.edu/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;MATCH=Technical+Definition+and+Description+Planning+Drop+box&quot;&gt;drop box&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; For
 this assignment, I will need to approve the product or process you
 will be describing, in order to be sure you do not select 
something that is too complex or too simple. I will respond to your topic choice as soon as possible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Activities due on Tuesday, June 10 by 11:59pm(ET)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;
Work on drafting your technical description/definition once you have received approval from your instructor to do so.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools for this Lesson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>