<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><AnnouncementsCollection><item><_announceId><![CDATA[4B0765501EF42A3ACE7CE8F53AE10000]]></_announceId><_author><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_author><_dateCreated>2014-02-21T13:16:18</_dateCreated><_startDate>2014-02-21T13:15:00</_startDate><_endDate>2014-11-28T13:15:00</_endDate><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_userId><![CDATA[EVERYONE]]></_userId><_sequence>0</_sequence><_agentId /><_agentData /><_announcement><![CDATA[&lt;!--FORMAT=2--&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;normalSpan&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;normalSpan&quot;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;small&gt;Can you believe today marks our first deadline already? I told you the course moves fast.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;By this evening, you should post an introduction to the  Introductions  forum, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t already. Remember, also, to reply  to a few of  your classmates. It&amp;rsquo;s important that we all start to get to  know each  other so we can work together as a community of writers.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Tomorrow morning, I&amp;rsquo;ll begin grading your Introduction  activity  which, as the syllabus states, is a component of your  participation  grade in the class. You&amp;rsquo;ll receive a letter grade for the  activity. When  I evaluate your work, I&amp;rsquo;ll basically be looking to see  how well you  followed directions. For instance, if your post does not  meet length  expectations, your grade will reflect that. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve  posted grades,  I&amp;rsquo;ll let everyone know&amp;mdash;this way, you won&amp;rsquo;t have to keep  checking the  gradebook to see if grades have been posted yet.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Tomorrow, we&amp;rsquo;ll also start Lesson 2 in the class. The focus of  Lesson  2 will be our first writing activity in the class. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk  more about  that in an announcement tomorrow.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt; &lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;In the meantime, keep up the good work with your  introductions. It&amp;rsquo;s  nice to be able to get to know you all, especially  since we&amp;rsquo;ll never  meet face-to-face in this class.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Professor Tripp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;]]></_announcement></item></AnnouncementsCollection>