<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[33765DE009A04A1CB67FD3E22DA1039D]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[F04C9CF1FA9E4DD089A1C236B6054CC3]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:04:35</_entryCreated><_sequence>5</_sequence><_id>11505d83-5531-4ceb-aa96-60608c53f4c7</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[F04C9CF1FA9E4DD089A1C236B6054CC3]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 5 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 2]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:04:35</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understanding the Writing Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the previous lesson you learned about the research process. This lesson extends that process to involve all aspects of writing. That is, the lesson covers the full process that workplace writers typically undertake as they are working on a piece of technical communication. Research is one phase of this process, but there are also other important phases. You&amp;rsquo;ve already been planning and drafting your Internet Resource Guide; this week you&amp;rsquo;ll focus on revising, editing, and proofreading. The tools Markel discusses should help you in this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although much of the advice in this chapter is covered in first-year writing courses, most people need a refresher about the stages of the writing process. In fact, many technical communicators simply have not worked out procedures for writing effectively and efficiently. Too often, they work in an ad hoc fashion, which can waste time and energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This chapter discusses the basic phases of the writing process: planning, drafting, revising, editing, and proofreading. It also extends the basic discussion of the writing process by covering word-processing tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the outline view,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;templates,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;styles,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;spell checkers,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;grammar checkers,&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;thesauri, and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;find and replace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because technical communication often involves creating complex collaborative documents that include many sections, you need to learn how to use word-processing tools. Of course, these tools have their limitations: templates tend to lock the writer into a certain organization for the document, spell checkers don't know whether the writer is using the correct word, grammar checkers often flag correct constructions, and so forth. But generally speaking, these tools will be an important part of your writing process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;plan a technical document using the steps outlined in the chapter;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;draft a technical document using the steps outlined in the chapter;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;revise, edit, and proofread a technical document using the steps outlined in the chapter; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;apply the techniques and tools to complete and assemble the parts of the Internet Resource Guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Wednesday, May 28 by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read Chapter 3 of &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Lesson+4+Commentary&quot; title=&quot;Lesson 4 Commentary&quot;&gt;Lesson 4 Commentary&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Complete the Self-Study Quiz for Chapter 3 of the textbook, available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bcs.bedfordstmartins.com/techcomm10e/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;front page of TechCommWeb&lt;/a&gt;. Pay particular attention to any questions that you miss, and review relevant parts of the chapter.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit your full draft of the Internet Resource Guide through your &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Internet+Resource+Guide+Draft+Forums&quot;&gt;team discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Friday, May 30 by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Carefully read each of the guides in your team forum (I will assign you to team groups of 3 or 4). Fill out a separate &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Internet+Resource+Guide+Review+Worksheet&quot; title=&quot;Review Worksheet&quot;&gt;review worksheet&lt;/a&gt; for each guide you read.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit the review worksheets for your peers&amp;rsquo; guides through the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Internet+Resource+Guide+Draft+Forums&quot;&gt; forum&lt;/a&gt;. You will want to use this forum space to continue discussion about your draft work, ask for clarification of comments, and ask follow-up questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Sunday, June 1 by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read the feedback your peers gave you and review the assignment sheet one more time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Revise your guide. Revisions should not be superficial; your final version should look significantly different from your original draft.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit your final paper to the &lt;a href=&quot;/section/content/default.asp?WCI=Goto&amp;amp;WCU=CRSCNT&amp;amp;MATCH=Internet+Resource+Guide+Final+Draft&quot;&gt;Internet Resource Guide drop box&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools for this Lesson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>