<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[CEC375D1020341ABB2359E9642FBCA6B]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[A87B4E47FEE64723B87D7C7D3A5421F9]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:07:20</_entryCreated><_sequence>8</_sequence><_id>a16dbe8b-8aa9-4a2c-b4ed-c58d73c3fa74</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[A87B4E47FEE64723B87D7C7D3A5421F9]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 8 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 3]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:07:20</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicating Persuasively&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persuasion is a difficult subject to learn in technical communication contexts, yet it is vitally important. A central problem of most technical communication is an inadequate understanding of what constitutes an effective argument. Although technical communication is often seen to be neutral, simply reporting facts and data, it&amp;rsquo;s actually a highly persuasive enterprise. For example, your resumes and cover letters not only provide factual information about you and your work experience but also present that information in a very particular way, highlighting certain things and subordinating others. The view of you that your resumes and cover letters advance is not a neutral view&amp;mdash;you are attempting to persuade your reader. Similarly, an instruction set may appear to be a simple, functional document, but in reality users make value judgments about processes based on the associated documentation. Technical communication, on some level, is always persuasive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What then are the assumptions that characterize a rhetorical, argument-based approach to writing? This is an important background to have before we look specifically at how technical communication employs persuasion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Discourse is purposeful; one way or another, for good or for ill, it quite literally has designs upon us. These purposes may be complex and they may be affected by many contextual variables, but it is useful for writers to articulate their purposes and to learn how to make choices to fulfill them.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writing arises out of situations; it does not come into being for no reason. Writing courses emphasize the importance of exigence, the need that brings about the writing. Sometimes the exigence is clearly external (you need to persuade the police officer not to give you a ticket), and sometimes the writer needs to argue it into place (you need to persuade the reader that your product is critical to their business).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writing is addressed to an audience. Writing courses emphasize the importance of considering audience and learning to write for different audiences with different expectations and assumptions.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writers need to make their main point clear to the reader.&amp;nbsp; This does not mean that they need to write traditional paragraphs, but it does mean that by the time the reader finishes the text, he or she should have a clear sense of what it is getting at. The main point may be complex and nuanced, but it should not be mysterious.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writers should expect to present evidence for their arguments, not just statements of belief. There are various kinds of evidence: authority, personal experience, narrative accounts, examples, and of course research studies.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Writers can learn how to develop arguments systematically, and the ability to do this will improve writing ability.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The rhetorical appeals to logic, emotion, and the character of the writer are not separate although they can be talked about individually; argumentation does not devalue emotional appeals although emotional appeals must be used responsibly.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Style is neither mere ornament nor mere correctness. Rather, style choices contribute to the persuasiveness of a document and will be different for different situations.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Design is neither mere ornament nor mere correctness. The design of pages contributes to a reader&amp;rsquo;s understanding of content. The design of visuals affects how people interpret a graph or table.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep these assumptions about persuasion in mind as you read this lesson and continue work on your job application package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;identify and respond to an audience's broader goals;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;describe common workplace constraints and their effects on technical communication;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;write a persuasive argument;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;recognize common logical fallacies;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;display a professional persona in technical documents;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;recognize the important role of graphics, design, and ethics in persuasion; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;use persuasive techniques in your job application package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Tuesday, May 28 by 11:59pm (ET) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read Chapter 8 of Technical Communication.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read the Lesson 6 Commentary.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit drafts of both your resumes and cover letters through your team discussion forum. Include copies of the job ads you&amp;rsquo;re responding to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Wednesday, May 29 by 11:59pm (ET) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Carefully read each of the resumes and cover letters in your team forum (I will assign you to team groups of 3 or 4).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fill out a separate review worksheet for each resume and cover letter you read. You&amp;rsquo;ll notice one question that asks you to evaluate whether your peers use action verbs, which were discussed in the previous lesson. I&amp;rsquo;ve provided a long list of action verbs that supplements the list in your textbook; this should be helpful in developing an appropriate style.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit the review worksheets for your peers&amp;rsquo; materials through the forum. You will want to use this forum space to continue discussion about your draft work, ask for clarification of comments, and ask follow-up questions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>