<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Folder><_lessonEntry><_entryId><![CDATA[A9BD6A6825214EC0AE4582A27025A215]]></_entryId><_objectId><![CDATA[C1C124492BBC4E4E8FD2909B31E1F967]]></_objectId><_parentId><![CDATA[ROOT]]></_parentId><_courseId><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_courseId><_editableBy>32</_editableBy><_viewableBy>2</_viewableBy><_tracking>0</_tracking><_hidden>0</_hidden><_password /><_userGroup><![CDATA[ALL]]></_userGroup><_startDate /><_endDate /><_entryAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_entryAuthor><_entryCreated>2014-02-13T12:06:31</_entryCreated><_sequence>7</_sequence><_id>3da9c992-46f1-4d05-af4b-f4c3197ec84f</_id><_parentEntryId /><_shortcutAction /><_responseCount>-1</_responseCount><_responses /><_properties /><_associatedRubrics /><_linkedLessonEntries /></_lessonEntry><_lessonObject><_objectId><![CDATA[C1C124492BBC4E4E8FD2909B31E1F967]]></_objectId><_objectType><![CDATA[FOLDER]]></_objectType><_editMask><![CDATA[MC_2013FAUP_dpt11_ENGL_202C_ALL]]></_editMask><_linkMask><![CDATA[*-*-*-*-*-*]]></_linkMask><_title><![CDATA[Week 7 Activities]]></_title><_subtitle><![CDATA[Project 3]]></_subtitle><_pageFormat>2</_pageFormat><_linkUrl /><_linkTarget><![CDATA[_self]]></_linkTarget><_objectEditableBy>32</_objectEditableBy><_iconUrl /><_helpUrl /><_objectAuthor><![CDATA[dpt11]]></_objectAuthor><_objectCreated>2014-02-13T12:06:31</_objectCreated><_deleted>0</_deleted><_attributes /><_pageText><![CDATA[&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparing Job Application Materials&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most students are willing to incur considerable expense to have their job application materials prepared for either print or the Web, but they are much less willing to put a similar effort into their content and expression. One result is that both the resume and the cover letter often contain basic writing errors. Potential employers have little to go on in evaluating your credentials except the letter and resume, so when those documents contain errors the employers must draw the logical conclusion that the applicant is either ignorant or lazy. This conclusion may not be accurate, but first impressions go a long way&amp;mdash;and you want yours to be strong and professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The typical resume and cover letter are often not ambitious enough for today&amp;rsquo;s competitive job market. Many students think it sufficient to show that they have credentials for the job. If the ad calls for a degree in mechanical engineering, students will say they have one, but they don&amp;rsquo;t elaborate on courses, assignments, and the like. The point should now be obvious: a lot of candidates are qualified for any position, but minimum qualifications will not ensure an interview. So we will spend class time reviewing sample resumes and cover letters, discussing how to persuasively present yourself as an applicant. We will also critique one another&amp;rsquo;s work, trying to find areas of weakness as well as of strength. In addition, we will look at different kinds of electronic resumes; both employers and candidates are very interested in the process of electronic job applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of this lesson you will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;plan an effective job search;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;describe the best ways to look for a position based on your field of study and experience level;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;design an effective resume and cover letter; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;understand the job application process as a rhetorical process that involves presenting your background and work in particular ways. (There is, of course, more than one way to present yourself; you&amp;rsquo;re looking for the best representation for a particular job.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activities due on Wednesday by 11:59pm (ET)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Read Chapter 15 of &lt;em&gt;Technical Communication.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Review the instructions for our third assignment, the Job Application Package, by reading the assignment sheet very, very carefully.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Review an example Job Application Package I&amp;rsquo;ve provided.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Search for potential jobs to apply for. When you&amp;rsquo;ve found two ads that you think will work, upload your selections to the drop box for instructor approval.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Submit your Planning Worksheet to the drop box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materials &amp;amp; Tools for this Lesson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/div&gt;]]></_pageText><_drmProtected>False</_drmProtected><_isShared>False</_isShared><_dRM /></_lessonObject><_logs /><_access /></Folder>